A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller personal papers, Ann C. Whitman - Politics, Series P FA351
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Stafford, Michael, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 454)
  Edward Gottlieb & Associates, public relations for American Revolution Bicentennial Committee, New York State.
- Stanton, Sanford, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 455)
  Government policy toward the press.
- Stassen, Harold, 1966-1967 (Box 20, Folder 456)
  Vietnam, United Nations world peace.
- Steele, Richard A., 1972-1973 (Box 20, Folder 457)
  Summer job, Seal Harbor.
- Stein, Andrew, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 458)
  Temporary State Committee on Living Costs, fuel shortage.
- Steingut, Stanley, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 459)
  Tax bill, flood relief.
- Stern, Henry Root, 1965-1966 (Box 20, Folder 460)
  Superintendent, State Insurance Department, Blue Cross, legislation, litigation.
- Stern, Philip M., 1971 (Box 20, Folder 461)
  Ann Whitman's reply to Mr. Stern's letter.
- Stevens, Theodore (Senator), no date (Box 20, Folder 462)
  Conversation notes.
- Strawbridge, David A., 1972-1973 (Box 20, Folder 463)
  NAR disclosure of assets.
- Streib, Clarence, 1965-1972 (Box 20, Folder 466)
  Editor, "Freedom & Union," advocate of Atlantic Community.
- Sulzberger, Arthur Hays, 1959-1973 (Box 20, Folder 467)
  Publisher, "New York Times," Connecticut & New York land values, "New York Times" fiscal condition.
- Swanson, Gloria, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 468)
- Swidler, Joseph C., 1970-72 (Box 20, Folder 469)
  Chairman, Public Service Commission, population & economic growth.
- Syz, Hans (Dr.), 1972 (Box 20, Folder 470)
  His art at the Smithsonian.
- T General (Box 20, Folder 471)
  Taber, John: 1959, U.S. Representative, Committee on Appropriations. Taft, Charles P.: 1966, Chairman, Fair Campaign Practices Committee, Inc., appeal, declined. Taubman, George, Jr.: 1967, NAR supporter in California. Taurog, Norman: 1967, Metro Goldwyn Mayer, Inc., NAR than you for courtesies. Tavares, de Sa, Hernane: 1963-1965, Brazilian Representative to the United Nations, United States-Brazil relations, Inter-American Council of Commerce. Taylor, Betsy: 1973, Wisconsin Representative, National Convention, requests autographed photo. Taylor, Marion Young (Mrs.): 1966, "Martha Deane" program, WOR-TV. Taylor, Maxwell D. (General): 1961, Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts, Inc., NAR's thank you for information. Teague, Bert: 1969, Vice President, Anderson-Nichols & Co., Inc., appeals. Tejera-Paris, Enrique: 1967, Ambassador of Venezuela, NAR thanks for courtesies. Teixeira, Roberto: 1967, appeal for job position in Brazil, International Basic Economy Corporation. Templeton, Robert (Mrs.): portraits by Mr. Templeton. Terry, Clarence (Mrs.): 1965, Marian Anderson Concert. Thacher, Thomas: 1962, Superintendent of Insurance, press release. Thayer, Robert H.: 1967, appeal for son-in-law re: New York State Arts Council. Thomas J. Rochelle, Inc.: 1971, porcelains. Thompson, Doris: 1967-1968, thanks for NAR gifts. Thompson, Herbert L.: 1968, Public Relations Officer, Spiro T. Agnew, Governor of Maryland, Kerner Commission Report. Thompson, Kenneth: 1966, Rockefeller Foundation, Husson College. Thompson, Ted: 1972, National Park Service, NAR thanks for Santa Fe trip. Thornton, Dan: 1967, storage of atomic waste. Tierney, Gerard Leo (Father): 1967, St. Peter's Roman Catholic Church, appeal. Tobin, Austin, Jr.: 1965-1967, Austin Tobin & Co., metropolitan transit in major urban areas, personal correspondence.
- T General (Box 20, Folder 472)
  Todd, Walter: 1966, Todd Associates, NAR thanks for Finger Lakes Region wine. Tolley, William Pearson: 1967, Syracuse University, Office of the Chancellor, correspondence re: election, State Board of Regents. Tool, Jean K.: 1965, Frye-Sill & Bridges, Inc., re: 1968 political campaign. Townsend, Oliver: 1965, Chairman, New York State Atomic and Space Development, delivery of nuclear fuel to Western New York Nuclear Service Center. Treadway, Richard F.: 1962, Treadway Inns International, State Liquor Authority. Treat, William W.: 1963, Republican National Committee, thanks NAR for visit. Treman, Allan H.: 1969, proposal for Cornell Aeronautical Lab, Buffalo. Tribbe, Richard S.: 1967, Director, Legislative Affairs, Trans World Airlines (TWA), Inc., NAR thanks for help. Trimper, George J.: Erie County Republican Committee, sends $500 checks for memberships in Governor's Club. Trufert, Ives P.: 1967, Chairman, French American Banking Corp. Truman, Harry S.: 1959, Truman's 75th birthday and NAR gift. Tung, Tran Van: 1964, South Vietnamese leader exiled in Paris, views on Vietnamese situation. Tuohy, Walter J.: 1964, NAR thanks for support in political campaign. Tupper, Stanley R.: 1965-1968, Executive Director, States Urban Action Center, Inc., U.S. Ambassador, Canada, U.S. Representative. Turner, Huntinton M.: 1967-1973, Executive Vice President, H. S. Koster & Co., French American Banking Corporation representatives to see NAR, Association to assist Negro business. Turpanjian, Martin M.: 1960, "Jersey Parade," Palisades Interstate Park Commission, irregularities denounced. Tyroler, Jan (Miss): 1867, Public Relations Consultant, feminine battle royal in Washington, National Federation of Republican Women. Tysen, John C.: 1966, Chariman of the Board, "Previews," Inc., request for photo.
- Tata, J. R. D., 1971-1972 (Box 20, Folder 473)
  Chairman, Tata Industries Private Ltd., Bombay, India; India-Pakistan problems, appeal for India.
- Taylor, George D., Jr., 1972-1973 (Box 20, Folder 474)
  Book to be written about NAR, Columbia Broadcasting System (CBS) documentary of family to be filmed at Pocantico Hills.
- Teller, Edward (Dr.), 1961-1973 (Box 20, Folder 475)
  Nuclear physicist, designed H-bomb, Lawrence Radiation Laboratory, University of California, Defense Council Advanced Research Projects Agency, Department of Defense Project VELA, detecting undergrand nuclear explosions, missile defense, references to several of Dr. Teller's publications and studies, personal correspondence.
- Thayer, Harry M., 1970 (Box 20, Folder 476)
  President, WGHQ, fines collected by Justice of the Peace, Town of Wawarsing (New York).
- Thayer, Walter N., 1966-1973 (Box 20, Folder 477)
  State Finance Committee, Campaign and fund raising planning, Thayer's advice 1974 race, personal correspondence.
- Thibault, Mona, 1968-1972 (Box 20, Folder 478)
  Resume, Elizabeth F. Boshart, NAR thanks for Southwest arrangements for trip.
- Thomas, Lowell, 1963-1973 (Box 21, Folder 479)
  Explorer, broadcaster, naturalist, wants to see NAR.
- Tishman, David (Mrs.), 1972 (Box 21, Folder 480)
  New York University Medical Center, theater benefit.
- Travia, Robert F., 1966 (Box 21, Folder 481)
  Federal Court Judge, legislative session, appeal for job, thanks to NAR for position with Chase.
- Tofany, Vincent L., 1967-1970 (Box 21, Folder 482)
  Commissioner, Department of Motor Vehicles, thanks to NAR for gift, press release May 11, 1970, statement by NAR prepared for meeting with President Nixon.
- U General (Box 21, Folder 483)
  U Thant: 1965, United Nations Secretary General, possible luncheon meeting. Uht, Carol: 1967, NAR's curator, art bill. Upton, Robert W.: 1959-1964, U.S. Senator from New Hampshire, press release supporting NAR, thanks from NAR. Uris, Bette: 1967, campaign director, The Rockland Foundation, fundraising for new cultural center. States Urban Action Center, Inc.: 1968, preliminary report, "Action for our Cities," Annual Meeting 1968, agenda, unemployment report.
- Underwood, H, Clark, 1973 (Box 21, Folder 484)
  Member Board of Trustees, Salem College, thanks NAR for contribution.
- Urstadt, Charles J., 1969-1973 (Box 21, Folder 485)
  Commissioner, Division of Housing & Community Renewal, Battery Park, New York City Mitchell-Lama Program, Twin Pines Village, Floyd Bennet Housing, Fort Tilden, New York City Rent Control.
- V General (Box 21, Folder 486)
  VanCott, George: 1967, correspondence re: sponsorship of legislation, repealing East Hudson Parkway Authority. Vandervort, Helen: 1962-1965, Women's Division New York State Exposition, NAR contribution to Art Exposition. Van Eyck, Rosemarie: 1963, Newton College of the Sacred Heart, thanks NAR for stay at Executive Mansion. Van Law, Eileen Alcorn: 1961, thanks NAR for gift. Vaughan, Robert: 1967, Metro Goldwyn Mayer, NAR thanks. Van Voorhis, John (Judge): 1961, NAR thanks for gifts. Van Wie, Evelyn: 1967, thanks NAR for flowers send while sick. Vasilew, Eugene: 1965, Harpur College, offers NAR suggestions on rhetorical problems and efforts, New Hampshire political campaign.
- Vail, Thomas, 1967-1972 (Box 21, Folder 487)
  Publisher & Editor, "The Plain Dealer," editorial on Rodman, NAR letter introducing Vail's son to Dartmouth.
- Van Wie, Diane, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 488)
  Executive Chamber, NAR thanks for help, thanks to NAR for gifts.
- Villere, Jacqueline, 1972-1973 (Box 21, Folder 489)
  John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts, Sales Manager, Executive Secretary to General Manager, appeal for position on NAR staff.
- Volpe, John, 1966-1972 (Box 21, Folder 490)
  Governor of Massachusetts, Secretary of Transportation, press release March 24, 1966 re: real estate, NAR appeal for Timothy Guiry entering Coast Guard Academy.
- W General (Box 21, Folder 491)
  Wagner, Robert: 1964-1970, Mayor, New York City, appeal to NAR to write note to Bob Dowling to be included in Dowling biography, declined. Wainwright, Stuyvesant: 1959, U.S. Representative, Suffolk County situation. Waldo, Thayer: 1947-1968, Inter-American Services, "Alton Evening Telegraph," wire editor, re: Latin America. Appeal for position as press secretary. Wilkeson, Ted: 1961-1967, encloses letter to President Kennedy re: military policies vs. scientific advice. Wallace, De Witt (Mr. & Mrs.): 1959-1965, "The Reader's Digest," Editor, appeal to NAR, re: westerly location of Interstate 87, Westchester, supports NAR with public expression of support on Medcalf-Montello Bill on alcoholism. Wallace, Hugh C.: 1971, Senior Vice President, Brown, Harris, Stevens, Inc., re: NAR recommendation of A. G. Marshall buying apartment from his firm. Wallace, Irving: 1964, writer, sends copy of "The Man" to NAR. Walsh, Gerald P.: 1959, NAR thanks for book, "Protracted Conflict." Walsh, John: 1966, Congressional liaison memo. Wampler, Cloud: 1963, Chairman, Carrier Corporation, Syracuse, New York, thanks. Wands, Robert: 1967, NAR thanks for photo album. Wanger, Walter: 1966, Panel on World Understanding, Symposium on World Affairs, Dartmouth College. Warburg, Edward M.M.: 1967, South Mall, art. Ward, Evans: 1959-1960, Treasurer, Westchester Republican County Committee. Ward, Paul Langdon: no date, President, Sarah Lawrence College, resume. Warner, Rawleigh, Jr.: 1966, NAR contribution to Center for Inter-American Relations. Warren, Earl: 1959-1964, U.S. Supreme Court, NAR birthday wishes, report to the President. Washburn, Abbott: 1967, political gathering. Washington, Ruth: 1965, thanks for support of service organization. Watson, Ann: no date, thanks to NAR. Watson, Nancy: no date, thanks for NAR for Outward Bound contribution. Watson, Richard: no date, cable re: trip. Watson, W. Marvin: 1973, gas sales to USSR. Watson, Thomas J.: 1959-1967, President, IBM, unable to take on NAR assignment. Watts, Milly Lee: 1967, invitation to dinner with NAR, declined. Watts, William: 1969, white House aide.
- W General (Box 21, Folder 492)
  Weaver, Sylvester L. (Pat): 1959-1968, Government private enterprise cooperation, politics. Webster, Edwin (Mrs.): 1963, thanks to NAR.] Weinberg, Philip H.: 1973, Advisory Commission on Quarter Horse Racing. Weeks, Robert (The Reverend): 1967, NAR contribution to State Training School for boys. Weingarten, Victor: 1968, President, Institute of Pacific Affairs, thanks to NAR. Weinstein, Moses: 1966-1967, Majority Leader, New York State Assembly, birthday wishes, Fort Totten. Weitman, Robert: 1967, thanks for Metro Goldwyn Mayer tour. West, Millard F., Jr.: 1968, NAR resignation from Metropolitan Club. Westberg, Ellen: 1963, Cook, Executive Mansion, NAR recommendation. Wheatley, Henry: 1967, Peace Corps, Venezuela. Wheatley, W. D.: 1961-1962, Rockefeller supporter, asks comment on book. Wheeler, Monroe: 1960-1970, NAR thanks. Whit, Lawrence B: 1962, NAR supporter. White, Theodore: 1965-1970, politics. Whitman, Charles S. (Mrs.): 1959-1960, husband born in Executive Mansion. Wickham, Don J.: 1964, Commissioner, New York State Department of Agriculture & Markets, National Grange Meeting, administrative matters. Wildey, Douglas R.: 1965, Editor, "Tarrytown News," story on Rockefellers, tax editorial. Wilkens, Emily: 1966, NAR thanks. Wilkins, Roy: 1962, Executive Secretary, National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, NAR contribution. Wille, Roland F.: 1967, Superintendent of Banks, New York State. Williams, B. B.: 1962, Cooper-Bessemer Corporation, thanks for John D. Rockefeller, Jr's creed. Williams, G. Mennen: 1959, Governor of Michigan, sends book on civil rights. Williams, Margaret S.: 1964, visit to Venezuela ranch. Williams, Walter: 1959, NAR speech to bankers. Wilm, Harold G.: 1961-1965, Commissioner, State Department of Conservation, personnel, parks & recreation, highways, Delaware River Compact. Wilmers, Gigi: 1963, NAR research staff, thanks to NAR. Wilson, Arthur: 1965, President, Virgin Islands Tours, NAR thanks. Wilson, G. H.: 1959, NAR supporter. Wilson, Jerome: 1973, personal correspondence. Wilson, Joseph: 1971, President, Xerox Corporation, Joslin Foundation, diabetes, politics. Wilson, Kathy: 1963, thanks to NAR. Winchester, Lady Bapsy: 1962-1963, Marchioness of Winchester, greetings to NAR. Winkler, Franz E.: 1967, President, Myrin Institute for Adult Education, social ills. Wirth, Conrad L.: 1966, NAR thanks. Wise, John: 1968, NAR thanks for ties. Wood, William J.: 1969, congratulations from NAR. Woodward, Harper: 1973, thanks from NAR. Wrightsman, Charles B.: 1967, thanks for hospitality. Wyckoff, Gene: 1966, staff, thanks from NAR.
- Walker, Wyatt Tee, 1966-1970 (Box 21, Folder 493)
  Special Assistant to the Governor for Urban Affairs, education, civil rights, University in Harlem, narcotics, breakfast with black clergy.
- Ward, C. D., 1972-1973 (Box 21, Folder 494)
  Office of the Vice President, briefing for governors, interest in Critical Choices Commission.
- Watson, Arthur K., 1972-1973 (Box 21, Folder 495)
  United States Ambassador to France, NAR daughter's trip to Paris, comment on NAR speech to legislature.
- Weinberg, Hanns (Mr. & Mrs.), 1970-1973 (Box 22, Folder 497)
  Chairman of the Board, Antique Porcelain Company, admission to United States for employee, New York State Labor Department, thanks for gifts.
- Weinberger, Caspar, 1973 (Box 22, Folder 498)
  Secretary, (United States Department of) Health, Education and Welfare, Federal welfare regulations.
- Weissman, Herman L., 1972 (Box 22, Folder 499)
  NAR trip to Israel, United States' policy toward Israel.
- Wells, John A., 1964-1973 (Box 22, Folder 500)
  Politics, memo re: John Fitzgerald Kennedy in 1964, Keating, Robert Fitzgerald Kennedy race, 1965 Lindsay campaign, NAR contribution, possible trip to Israel, post-1966 campaign, study, Goldwater, 1968 Presidential Campaign, special legislative session, Watergate.
- Wells, John A., 1964-1973 (Box 22, Folder 501)
- Wennar, Mildred, 1969-1973 (Box 22, Folder 502)
  Secretary to Commissioner of Motor Vehicles, license plate requests.
- Wenzl, Theodore C. (Dr.), 1969-1972 (Box 22, Folder 503)
  President, Civil Service Employees Association, negotiations.
- Wharton, Clifton R., 1973 (Box 22, Folder 504)
  Asia Society Meeting.
- White, Arthur, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 505)
- White, Shelley, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 506)
- Whiteman, Michael, 1972-1973 (Box 22, Folder 507)
  New York City corruption, judiciary appointments.
- Whitford, Richard L., 1971 (Box 22, Folder 508)
  Autographed photo.
- Whitman, Ann C., 1959-1973 (Box 22, Folder 509)
  Personal correspondence to Ann C. Whitman. Some of the other correspondence in this file may be misfiles of correspondence belonging in other individual's folders.
- Whitney, Cornelius Vanderbilt (Mr. & Mrs.), 1966-1969 (Box 22, Folder 510)
  Politics, 1968 campaign, Vietnam, horse racing.
- Whitney, John Hay (Box 22, Folder 511)
  Publisher, "Herald Tribune," Chairman of Board, Cowles Communication, politics, medical research, fund raising, 1968 Presidential race, 1961 Mayoral race.
- Wickwire, C. Lynn, 1973 (Box 22, Folder 512)
  NAR attendance at FISU (International Federation of University Sports), games at Lake Placid.
- Wiebe, Richard, 1973 (Box 22, Folder 513)
  Regionalization, Appalachian Development Highway, funding.
- Williams, Helen, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 514)
  Staff member, New York State Majority Leader Brydges Office.
- Willis, Charles F., 1960-1973 (Box 22, Folder 515)
  President, Great Alaska Corporation, Ruth Washington & Republican political strategy.
- Wilson, Lois J., 1973 (Box 22, Folder 516)
  National Governors' Conference Advisory Task Force on Human Resources.
- Wilson, Malcolm, 1962-1973 (Box 22, Folder 517)
  World's Fair, South Mall, admission to Nursing Home, birthday, legislature, Goodell & Lindsay, (United States Department of) Health, Education and Welfare role in city problems, Police Conference, Alfred Del Bello, clippings.
- Wishnick, Robert I., 1967-1973 (Box 22, Folder 518)
  1965 Lindsay Campaign debts, Governor's Club.
- Woods, George, 1973 (Box 22, Folder 519)
  Critical Choices Commission, inflation problems.
- Woods, Rosemary, 1966-1973 (Box 22, Folder 520)
  Nixon article, picture of Nixon, child advocacy report, cufflinks.
- Wyman, George K., 1970-1972 (Box 22, Folder 521)
  Commissioner, Department of Social Services, Supreme Court decision, resignation.
- Y General (Box 23, Folder 522)
  Yates, William J.: 1959-1968, real estate & insurance, General Motors plant in Tarrytown, road extension & rebuilding. Yen, Chia-kan: 1967, sends book to NAR. York, Herbert F. (Dr.): 1960, director of Defense Research & Engineering, consultation with General Schuyler for North Atlantic Treaty Organization. You Chan Yang: 1959, Korean Ambassador to United States, congratulations to NAR. Young, Edgar B.: 1961-1962, Executive Vice President, Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts, construction of New York State Theater. Young, Fred A.: 1965-1966, Presiding Judge, Court of Claims, Chairman, New York Republican State Committee, resignation as Chairman, Court of Claims report. Young, Whitney: 1966, clipping on busing.
- Yates, Polly, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 523)
  World Bank, French Legion of Honor.
- Z General (Box 23, Folder 524)
  Zeckendorf, William A.: 1967-1969, Stewart Air Force Base, New York's fourth jet airport, residence & industry complex, Development of Bedford-Stuyvesant, University in Brooklyn. Ziegenfelder, Rush: 1965, Parsons, Brinckerhoff, Quade & Douglas, engineers work for Metropolitan Transit Authority, Governor's Club. Zimmerman, Charles: 1965, President, Connecticut Mutual Life Insurance Company, Amendment to New York State Insurance Law. Zollikofer, W. W.: 1964, politics. Zwanzig, Otto E.: 1961, seeks International Basic Economy Corporation job.
- Zaretzki, Joseph, 1959-1973 (Box 23, Folder 525)
  New York State Senate Minority Leader, personal correspondence, request for judiciary appointment, declined, Transportation Bond Issues, new job for state worker.
- Miscellaneous Materials
  - Abortion, 1973 (Box 23, Folder 526)
    Gallup poll, clipping.
  - Adirondack Mountains National Park, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 527)
    Report on establishment of park.
  - Drug Abuse Program, 1973 (Box 23, Folder 528)
    Information manual, drafts of testimony on drug bill, figures, draft of drug bill, NAR notes.
  - Executive Chamber Paintings, no date (Box 23, Folder 529)
    Sigmund Rothchild appraisal of paintings.
  - Impeachment Letters, October-November 1973 (Box 23, Folder 530)
    Letters from the general public, urging NAR to use his offices and influence to get President Nixon to resign.
  - Impeachment Letters, October-November 1973 (Box 23, Folder 531)
  - Impeachment Letters, October-November 1973 (Box 23, Folder 532)
  - Miscellaneous Materials - Impeachment Letters, October-November 1973 (Box 23, Folder 533)
  - New York Metropolitan Region, 1960 (Box 24, Folder 534)
    Study, outline, press release.
  - Presidential Campaign Issue Book, 1964 (Box 24, Folder 535)
- Printed Material
  - Annual Legislative Message, 1959-1964 (Box 24, Folder 536)
  - Annual Legislative Message, 1965-1969 (Box 24, Folder 537)
  - Messages to the Legislature, 1960 (Box 24, Folder 538)
  - The Government of New York State, 1961 (Box 24, Folder 539)
  - Speeches, Remarks, Press Releases by NAR, 1960-1966 (Box 24, Folder 540)
  - New York: A State Can Meet Its Responsibilities, no date (Box 24, Folder 541)
  - Program: Cathedral Choir of Mother AME Zion Church, New York City, Concert in Honor of NAR, 1970 (Box 24, Folder 542)
- Oversized Material
  - Original Musical Score and Tape Recording by Anthony Menk (Box 25, Folder 543)
    From box 13, folder 311.
  - Maps (Box 25, Folder 544)
    Two maps showing possible sites for termini of the proposed Long Island Bridge, between Bayville (Long Island), New York, and Rye, New York.
    From box 14, folder 327.
  - "Reality House" Brochure (Box 25, Folder 545)
    From box 14, folder 344.
  - Final Proof, "Action for Our Cities," by States Urban Action Center (Box 25, Folder 546)
    From box 21, folder 483.